<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Examples on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/examples/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Examples on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tsh-website.netlify.app/examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TiSEM AirBnB Template</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/examples/tisem-airbnb-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/examples/tisem-airbnb-template/</guid>
      <description>Overview Using publicly available data from AirBnB (available via Kaggle.com), we illustrate how a reproducible workflow may look like in practice.
Check out our GitHub repository for all the details on how to clone the project and run it. Alternatively, continue reading below.
We&amp;rsquo;ve crafted this project to run:
 platform-independent (Mac, Linux, Windows) across a diverse set of software programs (Stata, Python, R) producing an entire (mock) paper, including modules that  download data from Kaggle, prepare data for analysis, run a simple analysis, produce a paper with output tables and figures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Reproducible Research Workflow</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/examples/simple-reproducible-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/examples/simple-reproducible-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this example, you find a simple make pipeline, which prepares (data-preparation) and analyzes (analysis) data using R, and creates some tables for a paper (paper) using LaTeX.
This is probably the most simplistic but still complete workflow, and thus highly recommended as a template to kickstart your projects.
You can check out this repository for all the details. Fork it/use it as a template - contributions appreciated!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
