<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Task-specific configurations on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/task-specific-configurations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Task-specific configurations on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/task-specific-configurations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Software Setup Overview</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/task-specific-configurations/software-setup-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/task-specific-configurations/software-setup-overview/</guid>
      <description>These pages should help you to get started setting up the computing environment on your machine ready.
Think your machine is already configured well? Then directly proceed to our tutorial on setting up efficient workflows to manage data- and computation-intensive projects. If necessary, you can come back to this section to make changes to your computer&amp;rsquo;s configuration.
Configure your computer Of course, there are many ways to set up a machine, and we do not mean to consider our way of doing to be perfect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Python for Web Scraping</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/task-specific-configurations/webscraping_drivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/task-specific-configurations/webscraping_drivers/</guid>
      <description>Web Scraping Using an Automated Browser Sometimes when we scrape the web, we need to automate our computer to open a web browser to gather information from each page. This is especially true when the site we want to scrape has content that is loaded dynamically with javascript.
We will install one package to help us here: Chromedriver.
Installing this stuff is operating-system specific, hence so are the instructions below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
