<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shoot Educational Videos on Tilburg Science Hub</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/open-education/educational-videos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shoot Educational Videos on Tilburg Science Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tutorials/open-education/educational-videos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is an educational video?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/open-education/educational-videos/educational-videos-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/open-education/educational-videos/educational-videos-overview/</guid>
      <description>What is an educational video? An educational video is meant for transferring knowledge to an audience. These often involve animations or presenting a slide deck. However, in most of the cases, you might want to show yourself - or the presenter - talking to the camera.
This guide will focus on the process of making these videos, not the content, and it&amp;rsquo;s aimed at teachers or contributors of Tilburg Science Hub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buying Equipment for Educational Videos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/open-education/educational-videos/equipment-edu-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/open-education/educational-videos/equipment-edu-videos/</guid>
      <description>Part 1 We&amp;rsquo;re going to present three different setup options ordered by increasing complexity. Keep in mind that more complex setups require a higher budget, more physical space, and more time to put in place. The higher setup time is one-off. Actually, in all three options it&amp;rsquo;s very quick and easy to start rolling once everything has been correctly configured for the first time.
Option 1 - Home Setup with a Webcam The need of expensive gear to produce high quality images is a myth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shooting Educational Videos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/open-education/educational-videos/shooting-edu-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/open-education/educational-videos/shooting-edu-videos/</guid>
      <description>Part 2 In this second part of our guide you will learn about the essential steps required to shoot educational videos.
Step 1 - Set Up Your Scene The first thing to do is to set up your scene, place your camera on a tripod, and compose the shot.
Here you face your first decision. You will need to choose what to include in your frame. This will dictate what focal length to use (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
