<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 16:13:31 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tsh-website.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow-overview/</guid>
      <description>Longing to put your knowledge from our workflow guide into practice? Then follow this tutorial to implement a fully automated workflow to conduct sentiment analysis on tweets, using our GitHub workflow template.
Objectives of this tutorial  Familiarize yourself with a robust directory structure for data-intensive projects Experience the benefits of automating workflows with makefiles/GNU make Learn to use Git templates for your own research projects Adjust the workflow template to  &amp;hellip;download different datasets from the web &amp;hellip;unzip data automatically &amp;hellip;parse JSON objects and select relevant attributes &amp;hellip;add new text mining metrics to the final data set using Python&amp;rsquo;s textblob &amp;hellip;modify the analysis in an RMarkdown/html document    Prerequisites  Computer setup following our setup instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command Line Tools</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/automation-and-workflows/commandline/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/automation-and-workflows/commandline/</guid>
      <description>A command-line interface or command language interpreter (CLI), also known as a terminal, is a means of interacting with a computer program where the user issues commands to the program in the form of successive lines of text (command lines).
Throughout the course we will emphasize use of the terminal and executing commands within it as our modus operandi.
Windows Users So that we can work as closely as possible to the Mac and Linux users we will install Cygwin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn R</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/develop-your-coding-skills/learn-to-code/learn-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/develop-your-coding-skills/learn-to-code/learn-r/</guid>
      <description>Chance is that sooner or later, you&amp;rsquo;re going to use R - one of the (if not the) most popular statistical programming languages in the world. It&amp;rsquo;s not only that R is free which makes it so good, but because thousands of people across the world use it, document it, and develop it further.
Let us warn you: the R interface may be scary at first sight, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re used to using Excel to do your data magic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/educational-support/educational-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/educational-support/educational-videos/</guid>
      <description>An educational video is meant for transferring knowledge to an audience. These often involve animations or presenting a slide deck. However, in most of the cases, you might want to show yourself - or the presenter - talking to the camera.
This guide will focus on the process of making these videos, not the content, and it&amp;rsquo;s aimed at teachers or contributors of Tilburg Science Hub. In other words, we will talk about the technical preparation and equipment needed to record such videos, not on how to create animations or compelling presentations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles for Good Coding</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/develop-your-coding-skills/tips/principles-good-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/develop-your-coding-skills/tips/principles-good-coding/</guid>
      <description>Write programs for people, not computers Make your code easy to understand for humans. If your code looks very complex or messy, you&amp;rsquo;re probably doing it wrong.
 Organization  Define functions that do one mayor step each, instead of one giant script doing everything Write short scripts that do one task each Document only what your code doesn&amp;rsquo;t say, but nothing else   Style  Use meaningful and short variable names Use consistent code and formatting styles (oneExample, one_example, example-one) Make use of indents in your code    Define things once and only once Let computers repeat and execute tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TiSEM AirBnB Template</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/examples/tisem-airbnb-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/examples/tisem-airbnb-template/</guid>
      <description>Overview Using publicly available data from AirBnB (available via Kaggle.com), we illustrate how a reproducible workflow may look like in practice.
Check out our GitHub repository for all the details on how to clone the project and run it. Alternatively, continue reading below.
We&amp;rsquo;ve crafted this project to run:
 platform-independent (Mac, Linux, Windows) across a diverse set of software programs (Stata, Python, R) producing an entire (mock) paper, including modules that  download data from Kaggle, prepare data for analysis, run a simple analysis, produce a paper with output tables and figures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Versioning using Git and GitHub</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/use-github/versioning-using-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/use-github/versioning-using-git/</guid>
      <description>Overview What is Git? Git is an open-source version control system, which allows you to keep track of your source files, and the changes you make to them. Using Git, you can roll back to any previous version of a file, and easily collaborate with team members.
Git &amp;ldquo;lives&amp;rdquo; on your local computer, and allows you to configure so-called &amp;ldquo;repositories&amp;rdquo; that track files and directories.
Tip Storing sensitive data
Git will eventually become the long-term memory of your project, and you may decide to make the repository public so others can learn from or use your work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribute to Our Mission</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/contribute-to-tilburg-science-hub/contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/contribute-to-tilburg-science-hub/contribute/</guid>
      <description>How to contribute to Tilburg Science Hub We&amp;rsquo;re glad for your interest in contributing to our project. Tilburg Science Hub is open-source, and as such, anyone can contribute! The process is really simple.
When writing for Tilburg Science Hub, please follow our communication style guideline. By contributing, you agree that we may redistribute your work under our license. In exchange, we will address your issues and/or assess your change proposal as promptly as we can, and help you become a member of our community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Python for Web Scraping</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/task-specific-configurations/configuring-python-for-webscraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/task-specific-configurations/configuring-python-for-webscraping/</guid>
      <description>Web Scraping Using an Automated Browser Sometimes when we scrape the web, we need to automate our computer to open a web browser to gather information from each page. This is especially true when the site we want to scrape has content that is loaded dynamically with javascript.
We will install one package to help us here: ChromeDriver.
Installing this stuff is operating-system specific, hence so are the instructions below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verify Software Setup</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/verify/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/verify/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s verify whether everything is properly installed Before we&amp;rsquo;re getting started, let&amp;rsquo;s verify whether you have properly followed our setup guide for R, Python and make in order to be able to run our workflow.
Our tutorial clips are recorded on Windows, but have been tested on a Mac, too.
Watch our video   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work with Large Files on GitHub</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/use-github/git-lfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/use-github/git-lfs/</guid>
      <description>Overview GitHub limits the size of files allowed in repositories. It warns you if you&amp;rsquo;re trying to push a 50MB file, and completely stops you if the push exceed 100MB.
However, even if it didn&amp;rsquo;t stop you, versioning large files would be very impractical. That&amp;rsquo;s because a repository contains every version of every file – that&amp;rsquo;s the point of versioning, right? Having multiple versions of large files cloned locally can become expensive in terms of disk space and fetch time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation with GNU Make</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/automation-and-workflows/make/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/automation-and-workflows/make/</guid>
      <description>Overview Make is a &amp;ldquo;build tool&amp;rdquo;, allowing us to control the execution of a set of command line statements to assemble pipelines that define what gets executed when. Using make, our entire workflow becomes transparent and reproducible.
Tip Why Build Tools?
Imagine you have built a complex project, consisting of dozens of datafiles and scripts. Also imagine you haven&amp;rsquo;t worked on the project for a few weeks, and now wish to continue your work where you left off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Reproducible Research Workflow</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/examples/simple-reproducible-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/examples/simple-reproducible-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this example, you find a simple make pipeline, which prepares (data-preparation) and analyzes (analysis) data using R, and creates some tables for a paper (paper) using LaTeX.
This is probably the most simplistic but still complete workflow, and thus highly recommended as a template to kickstart your projects.
You can check out this repository for all the details. Fork it/use it as a template - contributions appreciated!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Python and Julia</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/develop-your-coding-skills/learn-to-code/learn-python-and-julia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/develop-your-coding-skills/learn-to-code/learn-python-and-julia/</guid>
      <description>QuantEcon.org offers fantastic resources for you to get started using Python and Julia.
In particular, we would like to refer you to their open-source lectures, covering:
 Quantitative Economics with Python (and a fantastic, open-source book companion!) Quantitative Economics with Julia QuantEcon Data Science  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing an Academic Paper</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/develop-your-coding-skills/tips/write-academic-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/develop-your-coding-skills/tips/write-academic-paper/</guid>
      <description>The typical structure of an empirical paper in economics and business (or a master thesis, or a chapter of a Ph.D. thesis) involves the following sections, roughly in this order:
Structure of your paper Abstract Be as brief as possible and avoid word-by-word duplication with the introduction. State very clearly what the main take-away is for your paper. This can be a qualitative finding, but it can also be a number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Style and Writing Guide</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/contribute-to-tilburg-science-hub/style-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/contribute-to-tilburg-science-hub/style-guide/</guid>
      <description>Develop content for our target audience When contributing content to our platform, please address at least one of our target groups.
  Students and novice researchers who look for material developed, curated, and rigorously tested by professors and experienced users, ensuring them about quality and usability. Users may not know yet what (and why) they should learn the Tilburg Science Hub way of working. These users need to be onboarded first and guided through our content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download the Template</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/clone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/clone/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s download the template You can access the workflow template from here. We first need to download (or, as Git users would say, fork and clone) the template. The template then is accessible on our local computer, and we can start modifying it.
Watch our video to learn about the two ways of downloading a template. After that, work through the set of practice questions.
  Warning Clone/download the files where you have writing rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Environments</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/task-specific-configurations/software-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/task-specific-configurations/software-environments/</guid>
      <description>Overview The main advantages of using virtual software environments are:
  Ensures replicability:
 Environment specifies versions for each program and package used Ensures that specified versions are the right ones (environment does not forget to update specified version if the version is updated in a project)    Easy set-up on a different machine or the cloud: run environment setup to install all required software/packages.
  Keeps projects separate: adding or updating packages for one project does not affect others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/python/</guid>
      <description>Installing Anaconda Python Anaconda is a pre-packaged Python distribution for scientific users. To customize Python with packages and properly use it in combination with automation tools, we prefer a locally installed Anaconda distribution over cloud-based alternatives.
Watch our YouTube video, in which we walk you through the setup on Windows.
  Instructions Direct your browser to Anaconda download page and download the Python 3.x Graphical Installer for your machine. Sometimes, the download defaults to Mac, so if you&amp;rsquo;re on Windows or Linux, make sure to select the right version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snakemake</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/automation-and-workflows/snakemake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/automation-and-workflows/snakemake/</guid>
      <description>Snakemake is an easy to use workflow management system. Contrary to make, which was designed by computer scientists to build software, snakemake was designed for academic/professional research in Bioinformatics, so it may feel more intuitive for academic users.
Snakemake is a python package - so we can install using the default python installer, pip.
Mac &amp;amp; Linux Users: In a terminal window enter the command:
pip install snakemake followed by pressing the Return key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links to Other Great Initiatives</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/develop-your-coding-skills/tips/links-other-initiatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/develop-your-coding-skills/tips/links-other-initiatives/</guid>
      <description>Here we post some links to material we&amp;rsquo;ve discovered recently and find useful.
 Organizing data in spreadsheets Initial steps towards reproducible science Minimal example for make  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a New Building Block</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/contribute-to-tilburg-science-hub/create-building-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/contribute-to-tilburg-science-hub/create-building-block/</guid>
      <description>What is a Building Block? Building blocks are the DNA of our platform. They are small code snippets that users can independently &amp;ldquo;mix&amp;rdquo; to create something unique. Think of building blocks like LEGO bricks - each one with its own color, shape and functionality.
Check out our platform&amp;rsquo;s menu system to see in which categories we classify our building blocks. Want to add a new category? Let us know via a GitHub issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running the Workflow</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/run/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s run the workflow When starting to work with a template, we ideally like to see it &amp;ldquo;working&amp;rdquo; on &amp;ldquo;test data&amp;rdquo; first. In this way, we know we can extend it easily. As our template is fully automated, building should be easy - you only need to type make.
So let&amp;rsquo;s go ahead by first watching our demo on what happens if you run make in our template&amp;rsquo;s main directory. Then, you can proceed to our practice questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Path Settings Permanent</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/automation-and-workflows/environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/automation-and-workflows/environment/</guid>
      <description>For our workflow to be command line driven, we need to be able to call software from the command line. Whilst much of the software we have installed as automatically made this possible, it is not universally the case. Here we will make the extra few changes we need to complete the installation guide.
Windows Users (for Windows 8 and 10) You will need local administration rights for your computer, but you should have these on your personal computers or ones owned by the Department.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Packages</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/python-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/python-packages/</guid>
      <description>Anaconda&amp;rsquo;s Python Distribution comes with many of the packages we need to do scientific computing. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in all the packages included, click here and go to the Python 3.x tab.
pip Howevever, you may come across packages that are not installed by default. In this case we recommend you use the pip package management tool to install them.
Warning If your python 3 was found via python3 --version on the previous page, then type pip3 instead of pip for all of the following python plugins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R and RStudio</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/r/</guid>
      <description>R is a language for statistical computing and graphics. R&amp;rsquo;s use in the data science, econometrics and marketing communities has taken off over recent years and (at a bare minimum) should be considered as an open source replacement to Stata and SPSS.
Installing R Watch our YouTube video, in which we walk you through the setup on Windows.
  Go to the R website and download the most recent installer for your operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a New Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/contribute-to-tilburg-science-hub/create-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/contribute-to-tilburg-science-hub/create-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Create a new tutorial Tutorials teach our users how to combine individual building blocks into a &amp;ldquo;final product&amp;rdquo;. What that product really is is your choice.
When creating a new tutorial, you typically realize that you also need to create several new building blocks to make the tutorial work. So if you haven&amp;rsquo;t contributed to our platform yet, try contributing a building block first before starting on a brand-new tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspecting the Data-preparation Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/pipeline-make/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/pipeline-make/</guid>
      <description>Makefile of the data-preparation pipeline Up to now, we&amp;rsquo;ve learnt how to run make in our template. But we haven&amp;rsquo;t really learnt yet how the files in each of the particular pipeline stages are actually run. So, let&amp;rsquo;s now navigate to the data-preparation source code folder, and explore the makefile a bit.
Please first try to answer our questions below, and then watch our solutions.
Practice questions and answers   Inspect the syntax of the makefile in src/data-preparation/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stata</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/stata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/stata/</guid>
      <description>Installing Stata Stata is a proprietary statistical software frequently used by scientific users. First check with your local IT support whether your institution has Stata licenses available.
If not, you can purchase a copy on Stata&amp;rsquo;s website and follow the installation guide.
Making Stata Available on the Command Prompt You have just installed Stata. Later, we&amp;rsquo;d like to access Stata from the command prompt to automatically execute our source code. That way, you will be able to run a series of scripts in batch - which will significantly ease the burden of building complex data workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamViewer</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/automation-and-workflows/teamviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/automation-and-workflows/teamviewer/</guid>
      <description>Getting feedback on code or solving technical problems is crucial to your learning experience. When working remotely, we prefer to make use of TeamViewer, which allows us to remote-control your computer and help you right away (while you&amp;rsquo;re watching, of course!).
Installing Teamviewer To install TeamViewer, go to the TeamViewer homepage and download the installer for your operating system. We recommend you to install Teamviewer permanently. If you do not have admin rights, it&amp;rsquo;s fine to only select run once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dry-run of Make and First Modifications</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/wipe-rerun/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/wipe-rerun/</guid>
      <description>Dry-run of Make and first modifications to the data preparation scripts Sometimes, running a workflow may take hours, or even days. That&amp;rsquo;s why make supports so-called &amp;ldquo;dry-runs&amp;rdquo;, which you can initiate by typing make -n (for NOT run).
Watch our video to understand the intuition of dry-runs.
  Next, you will start to modify the scripts in this template. After all, you&amp;rsquo;re working on a template that you&amp;rsquo;re ultimately interested in modifying (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MATLAB</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/matlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/matlab/</guid>
      <description>MATLAB is a high-level programming language and an environment for numerical computation and visualization.
The University of Zurich has a campus-wide MATLAB license available to all students and employees. We will use this license to activate MATLAB on our machine.
If you do not have Matlab 2016a installed on your machine, please follow the installation instructions available on the University of Zurich&amp;rsquo;s page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Modifications</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/modifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/modifications/</guid>
      <description>More modifications, branching, and replacing input files Now let&amp;rsquo;s continue with a couple of advanced modifications to our workflow. We hope these convince you about the potential efficiency gains you can expect when working on data-intensive projects!
This time, you can directly start working on the practice questions below. Also take note of our additional explanations for each question.
Practice questions and answers   Please open textmining.py, and also provide the word count as an additional column.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perl</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/perl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/perl/</guid>
      <description>Overview Perl is an open programming language frequently used by engineers. We use Perl for text processing, such as processing tables generated by other statistical softwares.
Installing Perl Perl is already installed on Mac and Linux OS. Download Perl for Windows OS.
Making Perl Available on the Command Prompt Windows users For you to be able to use Perl from the command prompt, follow the steps below.
Warning Making Perl available via the PATH settings on Windows</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending the Analysis</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/analysis/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s modify the analysis We&amp;rsquo;re done with the data-preparation pipeline for now, and turn our attention to the analysis part of our project.
Admittedly, there&amp;rsquo;s not much here yet. Try fiddling around with the files a bit when you proceed to our practice questions and answers below.
Now let&amp;rsquo;s continue with a couple of modifications. You can directly start working on the practice questions below.
Practice questions and answers   Recall the powerful makefile we&amp;rsquo;ve introduced to you a while ago?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandoc</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/pandoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/pandoc/</guid>
      <description>Pandoc is an extremely useful &amp;lsquo;swiss army knife&amp;rsquo; for converting between different types of markup languages from the command line. For example, it readily builds PDFs with latex, and markdown - both of which are heavily used in academic research.
Linux Open a terminal window and type
sudo apt install pandoc to install pandoc from the command line
Mac Open a terminal window and type
brew install pandoc to install pandoc from the command line</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrap-Up</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/finish/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/more-tutorials/implement-an-efficient-and-reproducible-workflow/finish/</guid>
      <description>You did it! Congrats!!! You&amp;rsquo;ve finished our tutorial, and are now officially hooked to make.
Well, all fun aside, we hope you found this tutorial useful.
Of course, this is just one way in which to increase your research productivity. Here on tilburgsciencehub.com, we have more stuff available, so take your time to browse the page.
Oh, and to be complete, here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of what you&amp;rsquo;ve learnt.
Thanks for following through!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Editors</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/text-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/text-editor/</guid>
      <description>A good text editor lies at the heart of any serious programmer&amp;rsquo;s toolkit: It can do almost anything and makes you much more productive. The editors built into each program often are not the best option (we will find certain cases where you may want to use them).
Please download, install it along with the necessary packages and stick with it for at least the duration of the project or assignment to get a feel for how it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/latex/</guid>
      <description>LaTeX is a great typesetting system that includes a lot of features that allow to produce scientific documents. Many researchers use LaTeX to produce their papers and presentations, and many journals require authors to hand in their articles in a LaTeX format.
Installing a TeX distribution LaTeX is free to use. To use the LaTeX system, a TeX distribution needs to be installed. Detailed instructions for the different platforms are provided below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/overview/</guid>
      <description>Motivation When working on a project, most of us spend time thinking about what to create (e.g., a cleaned data set, a new algorithm, an analysis, and/or a paper and corresponding slides), but not about how to manage its creation. This results in two major issues, as outlined next.
Major issues in managing data-intensive projects
  we may lose sight of the project (&amp;ldquo;directory and file chaos&amp;rdquo;)
 Gradually, we write code and edit data sets, and put those files somewhere on our computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git and GitHub for Version Control</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/git/</guid>
      <description>Installing Git and Setting Up Accounts Git is an open source version control system (VCS) that has gained a lot of traction in the programming community. We will use version control to keep track of the files we write, and the changes we make to them. Using Git, we can roll back to any previous version of a file, and easily collaborate with others on source code.
Let&amp;rsquo;s create a GitHub account GitHub is a (commercial) platform which allows you to host your source code online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pipelines and Project Components</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/pipeline/</guid>
      <description>Overview It is useful to break down a project into its most basic parts, which we call pipeline and components.
  A pipeline refers to the steps that are necessary to build a project (e.g., prepare dataset, run model, produce tables and figures), and
  Components refer to a project&amp;rsquo;s most nuclear building blocks (e.g., data, source code, and generated temporary and/or output files).
  Later on, you will see that such a structure enables you to work on your project using multiple computers (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Management and Directory Structure</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/directories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/directories/</guid>
      <description>Overview From the previous section in this guide, recall that a project can be logically structured in the following components: raw data (e.g., data sets), source code (e.g., code to prepare your data and to analyze it), generated files (e.g., some diagnostic plots or the result of your analysis), a file exchange, and notes (e.g., literature, meeting summaries).
Below, we give you some more guidance on how to manage these components, by casting a prototypical directory structure that you need to set up on your computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating your Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/automation/</guid>
      <description>Overview Remember the different stages of a project&amp;rsquo;s pipeline? Let&amp;rsquo;s suppose we&amp;rsquo;re in the process of preparing our data set for analysis. For example:
 You wish to convert three raw data sets from Excel to CSV files. You want to merge these three CSV files and apply some cleaning steps. Finally, you want to save the final data set, so that it can be used in other stages of your project pipeline (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documenting Datasets</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/documenting-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/documenting-data/</guid>
      <description>Overview If your project contains data that has been newly created (i.e., which is not otherwise (publicly) available yet; including derived data sets), you are required to include a documentation of that data in your project.
Instances of &amp;ldquo;new data&amp;rdquo; may included, but are not restricted to be:
 data scraped from websites data gathered via APIs manually labeled data  e.g., to assign GDP per capita to a list of countries e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documenting Source Code and Pipeline Workflows</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/documenting-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/documenting-code/</guid>
      <description>Overview Documenting your project&amp;rsquo;s workflow, not only for others, but also for your future self (i.e., if you plan to continue working on the project after a while) is absolutely crucial to the long-term success of you as a researcher or analyst.
Typically, you would like to
 include a main project documentation, and one documentation each for each stage of your pipeline.  Main Project Documentation You should place a main project documentation in the root directory of your project (/my_project), and call it readme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Versioning using Git and GitHub</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/versioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/versioning/</guid>
      <description>Overview What is Git? Git is an open-source version control system, which allows you to keep track of your source files, and the changes you make to them. Using Git, you can roll back to any previous version of a file, and easily collaborate with team members.
Git &amp;ldquo;lives&amp;rdquo; on your local computer, and allows you to configure so-called &amp;ldquo;repositories&amp;rdquo; that track files and directories.
Tip Storing sensitive data
Git will eventually become the long-term memory of your project, and you may decide to make the repository public so others can learn from or use your work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaborating using GitHub</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/collaboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/collaboration/</guid>
      <description>Overview While you can use Git exclusively to keep track of your files&#39; version history, the real power of Git lies in collaborating on coding projects with others. Below, we outline how you can contribute to existing (open-source) projects that are hosted on GitHub.
Repositories versus Gists GitHub knows two types of &amp;ldquo;projects&amp;rdquo;. Full-fledged projects (e.g., for software development or research) are hosted in so-called &amp;ldquo;repositories&amp;rdquo;, which offer you the full range of development features available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checklist to Audit Data- and Computation-intensive Projects</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/checklist/</guid>
      <description>There is quite some material to cover to make sure your workflows become efficient, reproducible, and well-structured.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a checklist you can use to audit your progress.
    data-preparation analysis paper &amp;hellip;     At the project level       Implement a consistent directory structure: data/src/gen       Include readme with project description and technical instruction how to run/build the project       Store any authentication credentials outside of the repository (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Sharing</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/share-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/share-data/</guid>
      <description>Document and share data for internal and external use Maintain, document, and share your data with your team and the public
Workflow  Code and doc: Git Raw data, confidential (e.g., JSON files with like personal data it): stored at institution (or, in our case, some S3 bucket only we have access to) Data to be published: running code on confidential raw data  Make decisions on what your “public” or semi public data should consist of   Final data set  Published to Dataverse with links to code/github repository for documentation   Maintenance  Update code, rerun, re-publish    Steps Create  Create GitHub repository from template Store raw data on secure server (institution) Create data prep code to create derived version Create initial documentation from template Prototype workflow by running it with make  Share   Publish internally</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up and Using a File Exchange</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/infrastructure-choice/fileexchanges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/infrastructure-choice/fileexchanges/</guid>
      <description>File exchanges are essential to transfer data between different stages of your pipeline, and between different co-authors working on a project.
The key requirements of a file exchange are:
 the programmatic access (i.e., via command line tools), to data storage organized in directories and files, allowing members of the project to upload or download data, employing fine-grained access controls (i.e., to give users reading rights, or reading/writing rights).  Below, we show a few options that we&amp;rsquo;ve used in our research projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disclaimer</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/disclaimer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/disclaimer/</guid>
      <description>Tilburg Science Hub is part of Tilburg University. The information on this Tilburg Science Hub internet site has been formulated with the utmost care. This information may nevertheless contain deficiencies.
Should this be the case, we would appreciate your critical remarks at tsh@tilburguniversity.edu. Tilburg Science Hub is not responsible for any information supplied on its website or for the consequences of the use thereof. No rights can be derived on the basis of the data on Tilburg Science Hub website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/contribute-to-tilburg-science-hub/building-block-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/contribute-to-tilburg-science-hub/building-block-shell/</guid>
      <description>Title  Provide a brief overview of the issue to solve, or describe why this is a best practice.
Add any special requirements or attach a dummy data set if needed.
Code  # program to print Hello world print(&amp;#34;Hello world&amp;#34;) cat(&amp;#34;Hello world\n&amp;#34;) # Use in-line comments to explain your code Examples Provide examples to support the solution.
Example 1 !!! tip &amp;ldquo;Useful tip&amp;rdquo;
You can use special formatting options to highlight some paragraphs in your article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/contribute-to-tilburg-science-hub/tutorial-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/share-your-results-and-project/contribute-to-tilburg-science-hub/tutorial-shell/</guid>
      <description>Provide a brief overview of the issue to solve, or why this is a best practice. Explain the goal of this step and how it connected to the previous ones. Optionally, if you have assigned a task in the previous chapter, provide the solution at the beginning of this one.
The task Explain the solution step by step. If you can, record a video following our video guidelines for Tutorials. If there&amp;rsquo;s code involved, explain small snippets first and add more to build the final code, which you can display at the end of the chapter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/automation_workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/automation_workflow/</guid>
      <description>Specimen Body copy Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Cras arcu libero, mollis sed massa vel, ornare viverra ex. Mauris a ullamcorper lacus. Nullam urna elit, malesuada eget finibus ut, ullamcorper ac tortor. Vestibulum sodales pulvinar nisl, pharetra aliquet est. Quisque volutpat erat ac nisi accumsan tempor.
Sed suscipit, orci non pretium pretium, quam mi gravida metus, vel venenatis justo est condimentum diam. Maecenas non ornare justo. Nam a ipsum eros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/data/</guid>
      <description>Specimen Body copy Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Cras arcu libero, mollis sed massa vel, ornare viverra ex. Mauris a ullamcorper lacus. Nullam urna elit, malesuada eget finibus ut, ullamcorper ac tortor. Vestibulum sodales pulvinar nisl, pharetra aliquet est. Quisque volutpat erat ac nisi accumsan tempor.
Sed suscipit, orci non pretium pretium, quam mi gravida metus, vel venenatis justo est condimentum diam. Maecenas non ornare justo. Nam a ipsum eros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/housekeeping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/housekeeping/</guid>
      <description>Specimen Body copy Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Cras arcu libero, mollis sed massa vel, ornare viverra ex. Mauris a ullamcorper lacus. Nullam urna elit, malesuada eget finibus ut, ullamcorper ac tortor. Vestibulum sodales pulvinar nisl, pharetra aliquet est. Quisque volutpat erat ac nisi accumsan tempor.
Sed suscipit, orci non pretium pretium, quam mi gravida metus, vel venenatis justo est condimentum diam. Maecenas non ornare justo. Nam a ipsum eros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/portability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/tutorials/project-setup/principles-of-project-setup-and-workflow-management/portability/</guid>
      <description>Specimen Body copy Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Cras arcu libero, mollis sed massa vel, ornare viverra ex. Mauris a ullamcorper lacus. Nullam urna elit, malesuada eget finibus ut, ullamcorper ac tortor. Vestibulum sodales pulvinar nisl, pharetra aliquet est. Quisque volutpat erat ac nisi accumsan tempor.
Sed suscipit, orci non pretium pretium, quam mi gravida metus, vel venenatis justo est condimentum diam. Maecenas non ornare justo. Nam a ipsum eros.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
