<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics and Computation on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics and Computation on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automated Installation</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/automated-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/automated-installation/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Maecenas sed diam eget risus varius blandit sit amet non magna. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Vivamus sagittis lacus vel augue laoreet rutrum faucibus dolor auctor. Morbi leo risus, porta ac consectetur ac, vestibulum at eros. Donec ullamcorper nulla non metus auctor fringilla.
Section header Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Maecenas sed diam eget risus varius blandit sit amet non magna.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R and RStudio</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/r/</guid>
      <description>R is a language for statistical computing and graphics. R&amp;rsquo;s use in the data science, econometrics and marketing communities has taken off over recent years and (at a bare minimum) should be considered as an open source replacement to Stata and SPSS.
Installing R Watch our YouTube video, in which we walk you through the setup on Windows.
Go to the R website and download the most recent installer for your operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stata</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/stata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/stata/</guid>
      <description>Installing Stata Stata is a proprietary statistical software frequently used by scientific users. First check with your local IT support whether your institution has Stata licenses available.
If not, you can purchase a copy on Stata&amp;rsquo;s website and follow the installation guide.
Making Stata Available on the Command Prompt You have just installed Stata. Later, we&amp;rsquo;d like to access Stata from the command prompt to automatically execute our source code. That way, you will be able to run a series of scripts in batch - which will significantly ease the burden of building complex data workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MATLAB</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/matlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/matlab/</guid>
      <description>MATLAB is a high-level programming language and an environment for numerical computation and visualization.
The University of Zurich has a campus-wide MATLAB license available to all students and employees. We will use this license to activate MATLAB on our machine.
If you do not have Matlab 2016a installed on your machine, please follow the installation instructions available on the University of Zurich&amp;rsquo;s page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandoc</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/pandoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/pandoc/</guid>
      <description>Pandoc is an extremely useful &amp;lsquo;swiss army knife&amp;rsquo; for converting between different types of markup languages from the command line. For example, it readily builds PDFs with latex, and markdown - both of which are heavily used in academic research.
Linux Open a terminal window and type
sudo apt install pandoc to install pandoc from the command line
Mac Open a terminal window and type
brew install pandoc to install pandoc from the command line</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Editors</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/text-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/text-editor/</guid>
      <description>A good text editor lies at the heart of any serious programmer&amp;rsquo;s toolkit: It can do almost anything and makes you much more productive. The editors built into each program often are not the best option (we will find certain cases where you may want to use them).
Please download, install it along with the necessary packages and stick with it for at least the duration of the project or assignment to get a feel for how it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/latex/</guid>
      <description>LaTeX is a great typesetting system that includes a lot of features that allow to produce scientific documents. Many researchers use LaTeX to produce their papers and presentations, and many journals require authors to hand in their articles in a LaTeX format.
Installing a TeX distribution LaTeX is free to use. To use the LaTeX system, a TeX distribution needs to be installed. Detailed instructions for the different platforms are provided below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git and GitHub for Version Control</title>
      <link>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:02:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tsh-website.netlify.app/building-blocks/configure-your-computer/statistics-and-computation/git/</guid>
      <description>Installing Git and Setting Up Accounts Git is an open source version control system (VCS) that has gained a lot of traction in the programming community. We will use version control to keep track of the files we write, and the changes we make to them. Using Git, we can roll back to any previous version of a file, and easily collaborate with others on source code.
Let&amp;rsquo;s create a GitHub account GitHub is a (commercial) platform which allows you to host your source code online.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
