<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Write Your First LaTeX Document in 15 Minutes on Tilburg Science Hub</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/more-tutorials/write-your-first-latex-document/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Write Your First LaTeX Document in 15 Minutes on Tilburg Science Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tutorials/more-tutorials/write-your-first-latex-document/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Fine Art of Typesetting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/more-tutorials/write-your-first-latex-document/what-is-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/more-tutorials/write-your-first-latex-document/what-is-latex/</guid>
      <description>The Design Philosophy In this tutorial, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn to write your very first document using \(\LaTeX\)within 15 minutes.
$\LaTeX$ is a professional typesetting system widely used in academia because of its high-quality output and the relatively ease of use in setting up complex documents, like journal articles, books, technical reports, and similar.
One of its main features is that it separates the writing and the formatting stages - or the content and its presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup LaTeX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/more-tutorials/write-your-first-latex-document/setup-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/more-tutorials/write-your-first-latex-document/setup-latex/</guid>
      <description>Installation The first step is to setup a \(\TeX\)distribution on your machine.
 If you haven&amp;rsquo;t done it yet, you can read our guide on how to install $\LaTeX$:  How to Install $\LaTeX$ Once you&amp;rsquo;ve installed it, you&amp;rsquo;ll need a text editor to work with. We recommend Atom, a free and cross-platform editors with great functions and extra packages. You can download Atom from its official website or read the instructions from our Building Block.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your First Article</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/more-tutorials/write-your-first-latex-document/your-first-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/more-tutorials/write-your-first-latex-document/your-first-article/</guid>
      <description>The Preamble The preamble is the first section of your .tex file. It comes before the the text of the document itself.
The preamble always starts with the definition of a &amp;ldquo;document class&amp;rdquo;. This is where you tell \(\LaTeX\)what kind of document you&amp;rsquo;re writing: an article, a book, a letter&amp;hellip; More on that later.
You can then continue specifying additional information and packages in the preamble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add a Bibliography</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/more-tutorials/write-your-first-latex-document/bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/more-tutorials/write-your-first-latex-document/bibliography/</guid>
      <description>Please notice that there are different ways to include a bibliography in \(\LaTeX\), namely bibtex, natbib, and biblatex. In this tutorial, we will deal with bibtex only. For more advanced uses, consider researching which system works best for you.
Create a .bib File A .bib file contains all the bibliographic information for your document. Think of it as a sort of database of all the references you may want to include in your article (but you don&amp;rsquo;t have to necessarily).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Tips</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/more-tutorials/write-your-first-latex-document/latex-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tutorials/more-tutorials/write-your-first-latex-document/latex-tips/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations! You&amp;rsquo;ve completed this tutorial. Here are some useful tips when writing with \(\LaTeX\).
Specify The Encoding It&amp;rsquo;s always a good idea to specify the encoding of your document to allow characters beyond ASCII to be visible. It&amp;rsquo;s recommended to use UTF-8. Unless you know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing, simply add this in your preamble:
\usepackage[utf8]{inputenc} Use Labels This will change your life. One of the greatest features and reasons why you should use $\LaTeX$ for complex documents.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
