<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Examples on Tilburg Science Hub</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/examples/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Examples on Tilburg Science Hub</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Reproducible Research Workflow with AirBnB Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/examples/reproducible-workflow-airbnb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/examples/reproducible-workflow-airbnb/</guid>
      <description>Overview Using publicly available data from AirBnB (available via Kaggle.com), we illustrate how a reproducible workflow may look like in practice.
Check out the GitHub RepositoryWe&amp;rsquo;ve crafted this project to run:
 platform-independent (Mac, Linux, Windows) across a diverse set of software programs (Stata, Python, R) producing an entire (mock) paper, including modules that  download data from Kaggle, prepare data for analysis, run a simple analysis, produce a paper with output tables and figures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Reproducible Research Workflow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/examples/simple-reproducible-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/examples/simple-reproducible-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this example, you find a simple make pipeline, which prepares (data-preparation) and analyzes (analysis) data using R, and creates some tables for a paper (paper) using LaTeX.
This is probably the most simplistic but still complete workflow, and thus highly recommended as a template to kickstart your projects.
You can check out this repository for all the details. Fork it/use it as a template - contributions appreciated!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Interactive Shiny App of Google&#39;s COVID-19 Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/examples/google-covid-shiny-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/examples/google-covid-shiny-app/</guid>
      <description>Overview This example illustrates how to create a Shiny app which allows you to interactively explore Google’s COVID-19 Community Mobility Reports of the Netherlands through an intuitive visual interface (see the live version here).
How to create it 1. Skeleton The Shiny library helps you turn your analyses into interactive web applications without requiring HTML, CSS, or Javascript knowledge, and provides a powerful web framework for building web applications using R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Trends in the Cars Dataset with Regression Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/examples/exploring-regression-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/examples/exploring-regression-results/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this example, we analyze the relationship between a car&amp;rsquo;s speed and the stop distance. First, we check the model assumptions and screen for potential outliers. Second, we export our regression results into a format that you can easily copy into word processing software. Third, we build a scatter plot with the trend line on top of it. Fourth and last, we make predictions for unseen data points.
How to create it 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Reproducible Workflow Using Snakemake and R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/examples/reproducible-workflow-snakemake-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/examples/reproducible-workflow-snakemake-r/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a template for a reproducible research project that uses Snakemake and the R programming language.
We use Snakemake to construct a set of rules to build our workflow from start to finish, starting with some data cleaning, running some regressions, constructung figures and tables, and then finishing with compiling a pdf article and slides.
We believe this mimics an approximate workflow of most empirical research in social sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
